madbarz.com 2019-05-17

# Privacy policy

##  Data Protection Statement 

The protection of your personal data is of high importance to Madbarz Group Kft. Therefore, we comply with all legal requirements when we collect and process your personal data. Below you can find detailed information about the scope and purpose of collecting data. 

Use of the Madbarz website and Madbarz App means you consent to this privacy statement. 

If you have any questions or comments, do not hesitate to contact our Support team at [madbarz@madbarz.com](mailto:madbarz@madbarz.com) . 

Thank you for being a part of the Madbarz community! 

## Table of Contents

  * Principle of anonymous data use
  * Personal data
  * Collecting and processing personal data
  * Registration of your Madbarz account
  * What do we use your information for?
  * Data collection, processing and use within Madbarz ecosystem: 
    * General Use 
    * Madbarz Premium
    * Access Rights
    * Contact Form
    * Newsletter
    * Cookies
    * Pixels
    * Google Analytics
    * Google Adwords
    * Double Click by Google
    * Google Tag Manager
    * Facebook Custom Audience
    * Mixpanel
    * Microsoft Azure
    * AppsFlyer
    * Hotjar
  * Third party data transfer
  * How do we protect your information?
  * Third party links
  * Amendments to the Data Protection Statement
  * Changes to our Privacy Policy
  * Your Consent 
  * Data Controller
  * GDPR Rights
  * Contact Us

## Principle of anonymous data use

In principal, Madbarz website can be used without providing personal data, while our App requires registration. 

When you access our website, some information, such as IP address, is transferred. You are also providing information about the terminal device used (PC, smartphone, tablet, etc.), the browser used (Google Chrome, Safari, Firefox, etc.), time of visit to the website, the so-called referrer and quantity of data transferred. 

We cannot use these data to identify an individual user. We only use this information to determine how attractive our offer is and to improve its performance or contents, if necessary, and make its design even more appealing to you.

However, in the case of static IP address, personal identification is possible by RIPE query in individual cases, although we do not perform this. 

Nevertheless, Madbarz website is accessible for both static and dynamic IP addresses assigned.

## Personal data

“Personal data” are details of personal or material circumstances regarding a specific or identifiable natural person. 

These include, for example; your real name, address, phone number or date of birth.

## Collecting and processing personal data

Personal data are collected by us, only if you supply them to us, for example when you contact us, in particular by registering a Madbarz account, placing an order, requesting information or publishing personal data in Madbarz app in your profile or in the feed.

## Registration of your Madbarz account

In order to experience the full Madbarz experience, we require you to register. We collect information from you when you register on our Service. 

Providing this information allows you to subscribe to our Premium services, buy our digital products and use our App freely.

We require the following data for registration:

  * Name 
  * E-mail address
  * Password
  * Country
  * Gender
  * Age
  * Fitness level
  * Objective

You must acknowledge our data protection regulations and accept our Terms of Service, cancellation and ban conditions. 

When using the Service, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your mailing address, photo, phone number or credit card information. 

As a part of the Service we also might collect personal information about your exercise routines, diet, fitness and health status. The information is used as an essential part of the Service. 

We also reserve the right to ban your profile in case of any violations to our term of service.

Further, we offer you the possibility to create your Madbarz account via your Facebook account. You can register or log in with us by your Facebook account, if you simply use the Facebook button when registering your Madbarz account. You will then be directed to the Facebook page (where you must log in or you need to have an account) and you will be told which data on Facebook we need from you, that is, first of all, your public profile information, such as name, surname, gender and e-mail address which you have saved there. This is necessary for identification, so that a secure Madbarz account can be created for you. Your Facebook profile and your Madbarz account are permanently linked by the e-mail address. We save your email data here and we will contact you at this address with information, if necessary. We also take note of your registration with us via Facebook. As soon as you log in to Facebook, you can also log in with us. Without your consent, we will not forward any of your data to Facebook. 

Important: We do not find out your Facebook access data at any point and we have no possibility to post anything on your Facebook profile, without it having been approved by you separately. You can find out how Facebook handles privacy settings by consulting the Facebook Data Protection Policy (https://www.facebook.com/policy.php) and Terms and Conditions of Use (https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms); there you will also find the valid provisions for all above-mentioned possibilities of logging in and registering with us. 

##  What do we use your information for? 

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience (Your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs) 
  * To improve our website and app (We continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you) 
  * To improve customer service (Your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)
  * To process transactions (Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.) 
  * To send periodic emails (The email address you provide may be used to send you information, newsletter, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.)
  * To tailor our advertising efforts to best suit your interests 

Note that when you share and communicate using our products and/or services (i.e. participate in discussions, respect and comment on other users’ workouts, etc.), the information you provide in that manner on our site and app will be publicly available to all other users of our services. In some cases, people you share and communicate with may download and/or re-share this content with others on and off our services.

## Data collection, processing and use within Madbarz ecosystem

#### General Use

To use our Madbarz App or advanced website features, you must have a Madbarz account. You have already found out above what data are collected for this purpose. To provide you with the best Madbarz experience possible, our approach is partly based on publishing specific information of our users, i.e. even your information. 

This introduction includes the following information, in particular: 

  * public profile (photo, name, surname, training location, motivation) 
  * condition (estimated fitness level, desired objective) 
  * training information (period and type of training, total number of training sessions, photo)
  * followed by/follows (person who follows the user, person followed by the user) 

You become visible in Madbarz App with the data in your public profile. This information helps other users to find you in Madbarz App. At the same time, other users can see your name and surname (if provided), your published workouts, and your profile photo, and they can recognise you by this information, if necessary. 

Madbarz app will save all your successfully completed workouts, as well as related information, such as self-uploaded photos or comments. 

Other users can see these data and can consider them as incentive for themselves, leave comments or decide whether they want to follow you.

Moreover, our app also provides the users with the possibility to be followed ("Followed by") to support or encourage them in their training experience, or to compete with one another. For this purpose, users can be searched for by the name registered in the public profile, and if connected to your Facebook profile, your friends will be presented to you via suggestions. 

You will be notified about new followers on the website or mobile App by push message. Thus, some of your information is also available to other users in Madbarz App, irrespective of whether it is accessed on the website or in the relevant mobile Apps. 

If you do not want to make it possible to link your performance to yourself, you are free to refrain from providing any personal data on your profile or training sessions and linking your account to Facebook. Moreover, you should not save any training photos. 

For this reason, we have ensured that each user can change their personal information which can be viewed by other users and each user is free to use their own name or a fictitious name. 

### Madbarz Premium

If you bought Madbarz Premium, you will receive access to our Workout Programs, tailored by your provided fitness level and preferences.

If you have sustained a serious injury and therefore cannot do any training now, you can suspend your subscription for the period of your injury. For this purpose, you can notify our support team about your injury on a voluntary basis. The support team will only process the information, which subsequently becomes anonymous, as the basis for the relevant suspension of Madbarz premium.

### Access Rights

We need these access options and information to ensure the technical functioning of our App and provision of the services offered with the App, in particular to be able to access your camera or your photos, to determine your activity or to send you push messages to inform you about new followers or comments. During the installation procedure or before you use the App for the first time, we request permission to access individual functions and information. We only access these functions if you give us your approval. You can manually revoke the access rights in the settings for each operating system. You can find out how this works in the manufacturer instructions for your mobile OS. However, please note that you can use the App only to a limited extent or you cannot use it at all without the relevant approval.

Before you use the App for the first time, we will request the following rights for the purpose described below: 

  * Camera - taking photos for profile/feed 
  * Photo library - selection of photos for profile/feed
  * Push messages - variety of notifications
  * Mobile data/WLAN - use of internet and downloading of content

### Contact Form

Feel free to always contact us by e-mail or by an online contact form. Obviously, we will use the personal data provided to us in this way only for the purpose for which you make them available to us when you contact us. 

If we request entries in our contact form which are not required for establishing contact, we have marked them as optional (*). 

We use these data to specify your query and to handle your issues more effectively. Providing these data is expressly voluntary and with your consent. If the data in question refer to communications channels (for example, e-mail address), you also give consent for us to contact you or resolve your issue by these communications channels.

### Newsletter

You can subscribe to our newsletter, if you want to receive regular news updates or information from us about selected topics and products. We need your valid email address for subscription. 

You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time and revoke your given consent for the future. To do this, please click the relevant button in the newsletter you received. 

### Cookies

Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow it) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information 

We use cookies to help us remember that you’ve logged into Madbarz, understand and save your preferences for future visits and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

Most browsers accept cookies automatically. If you want to prevent cookies from being saved, you can select the "Accept no cookies" option in your browser settings. To find out exactly how this works, you can consult the instructions of your browser manufacturer. You can delete the cookies, which have already been saved on your PC at any time. We would like to note that our website service can only be used to a limited extent without cookies.

### Pixels

A tracking pixel (also called 1x1 pixel or pixel tag) is a graphic with dimensions of 1x1 pixels that is loaded when a user visits a website or opens an email, and is used to track certain user activities.

Every time you open our website, we record how often it is visited and clicked on by using tags on our website, so-called tracking pixels, likewise without any interference and intervention for your PC.

###  Google Analytics 

Madbarz App and Website both use Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses the so-called "cookies". The information about your use of this website generated by cookies is usually forwarded to and saved on a Google server in the USA. However, due to activating IP anonymisation on this website, your IP address is shortened beforehand by Google in member states of the European Union or other states which are parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. 

Only in exceptional cases is the full IP address forwarded to a Google server in the USA, and shortened there. On behalf of the providers of this website, Google uses this information to evaluate your use of the website, compile reports about the website activities and supply other services related to the website use and internet use to the website provider. 

The IP address transferred from your browser within the framework of Google Analytics is not combined with other Google data. You can prevent the cookies from being saved by the relevant settings of your browser software. However, we would like to point out that in this case it may not be possible to fully use all functions of this website. 

You can prevent Google from collecting cookie-generated data about your use of the website (including your IP address) and from processing these data, if you download and install the browser plug-in available at the following link (http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). You will find more information at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout or at https://www.google.de/intl/en/policies/ (general information about Google Analytics and data protection). You can find more information here www.google.com/privacy/privacy-policy.html. 

###  Google AdWords 

To draw attention to our services, we place advertisements in Google AdWords. They are inserted according to search queries in Google Services. On the page with our contact forms, cookies are used to register how many users found us thanks to one of our advertisements. We can optimise our advertisements thanks to the anonymous statistics acquired in this way. Cookies are saved by Google when the advertisement is clicked on and can be prevented by the settings of your browser. In this case, your visit to our website is not included in the anonymous user statistics. You can find more information in Google website statistics. 

### DoubleClick by Google

DoubleClick by Google is a service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). DoubleClick by Google uses cookies to show you the advertisements which are relevant for you. In the process, a pseudonym identification number (ID) is assigned to your browser to check which advertisements were inserted in your browser and what advertisements were seen. The cookies contain no personal data. The use of DoubleClick cookies only helps Google and our partner websites to place the advertisements based on previous visits to our or other websites on the internet. The information generated by cookies is forwarded by Google to a server in the USA, and saved there for analysis. Google transfers data to third parties only based on legal regulations or within the framework of the commissioned data processing. Google will never combine your data with other data collected by Google. 

You can prevent Google from collecting the cookie-generated data about your use of the website and from processing these data, if you download and install the browser plug-in available in the section on DoubleClick deactivation extension: https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/ 

###  Google Tag Manager 

We would like to point out that we use Google Tag Manager. Google Tag Manager itself does not collect any personal data. Tag Manager simplifies our integration and management of tags. Tags are small code components which are used for, among other things, measuring traffic and visitor behaviour, identifying the effects of online advertisement and social channels, setting up remarketing and organising target groups, as well as testing and optimising the websites. We only use Google Analytics, DoubleClick and HubSpot. If you have performed deactivation, Google Tag Manager will take this deactivation into account. You will find more information about Google Tag Manager at: https://www.google.com/intl/de/tagmanager/use-policy.html

### Facebook Custom Audience

Custom Audiences, a product of Facebook (Facebook Custom Audiences 1601 S. California Avenue, Palo https://www.google.com/intl/de/tagmanager/use-policy.htmAlto, CA, 94304), is also used within the framework of use-based online advertisement.

In principle, a non-reversible and not personal hash total (hash value) from your use data is generated in the process, which can be transferred to Facebook for analysis and marketing purposes. A Facebook tracking pixel is also set up on our website to this end. Information about your activities on the website (e.g. surfing behaviour, sub-pages visited, etc.) is collected in the process. 

Your IP address is saved and used for the geographical adaptation of advertisements. You have the opportunity to object to targeting via the following link: (https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences). 

You will find more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and subsequent data processing and use, as well as privacy settings in the Data Protection Policy of Facebook (https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)

### Mixpanel

Mixpanel is a business analytics service company. It tracks user interactions with web and mobile applications and provides tools for targeted communication with them. 

Its tool-set contains in-app A/B tests and user survey forms. Data collected is used to build custom reports and measure user engagement and retention. Mixpanel works with web applications, in particular SaaS, but also supports mobile apps.

As between Mixpanel and our customers, Mixpanel is the “data processor” and the customer is the “data controller”, as such terms are defined under the GDPR. The data controller collects data from our data subjects (i.e., a customer’s end users) and says how and why personal data is processed. The data processor receives the data from the data controller and acts upon instruction from the data controller. 

Google and Mixpanel use the anonymous information on our behalf to evaluate the use of Madbarzs and to prepare reports for us about your activities in the Madbarz app. 

###  Microsoft Azure 

We use Microsoft Azure Servers and Services for storing our services and your personal data. 

Microsoft Azure services are developed using the Microsoft Secure Development Lifecycle which incorporates privacy-by-design and privacy-by-default methodologies. Azure and related tools can help you comply with GDPR data protection requirements by providing ways to secure/encrypt personal data at rest and in transit, detect and respond to data breaches, and facilitate regular testing of security measures. 

Learn more about Microsoft Azure Privacy Policy here: https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/trustcenter/privacy 

### AppsFlyer

Madbarz uses AppsFlyer, an analysis service of AppsFlyer Ltd. The information about the use of Madbarz generated by AppsFlyer is usually transferred to a server outside Croatia and saved there. Google and AppsFlyer Ltd. use the anonymous information on our behalf to evaluate the use of Madbarzs and to prepare reports for us about your activities in the Madbarz app. 

You can limit the way in which Google Analytics and AppsFlyer function even further in the data protection settings of your device. 

You can also send an e-mail to privacy@appsflyer.com, if you do not want to allow AppsFlyer. You can find more information about data protection at Google here (https://www.google.de/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

##  Third Party Data Transfer 

In principle, your data are not transferred to third parties, unless we have a legal obligation to do so, or forwarding data is necessary for the performance of the contractual relationship, or you have given us express prior consent to forward your data. External service providers and partner companies, such as online payment providers or the shipping companies commissioned with delivery, receive your data only if it is required for execution of your order. But in these cases the scope of the transferred data is limited to the necessary minimum. If our service providers come into contact with your personal data, we guarantee that they observe the regulations of data protection law in the same way. Please also note the relevant data protection policies of the providers. 

The relevant service provider is responsible for the content of third-party services, whereby we perform reasonable checks to find out if the service complies with the statutory requirements.

## How do we protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your personal information. 

We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.

##  Third Party Links 

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. 

We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites. 

## Amendments to the Data Protection Statement

We reserve the right to amend or adjust this Data Protection Statement at any time subject to compliance with the applicable data protection regulations.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page.

##  Your Consent 

By using our services and/or products, you consent to our privacy policy. 

## Data Controller

Madbarz Kft. processes Personal Data both as a Processor and as a Controller, as defined in the Directive and the GDPR. 

The Madbarz entity which you as a User entered in an agreement with when using Madbarz platform, will be the Controller for the User data, as outlined above in previous sections. 

Madbarz adheres to the Directive of 1995 and GDPR from May 25th 2018 Consequently. All your data is stored on our Microsoft Azure Cloud Computing Servers and Services indefinitely. 

## GDPR Rights

Based on the legal regulations in the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) you may contact us free of charge with questions about the collection, processing and use of your personal data and their correcting, blocking or deleting, or revoking the consent given. 

We shall respond to all reasonable queries free of charge and as soon as possible based on the applicable law. 

We would also like to point out that you have the right to correct false data and delete personal data, if this is not contrary to any statutory retention obligation. These compiled data protection regulations or the Data Protection Statement shall be continuously adjusted in the course of further development of the internet. Amendments shall be announced on this website beforehand. 

To stay informed about current data protection regulations, you should regularly visit this website. You can send your queries free of charge to the following e-mail: [madbarz@madbarz.com](mailto:madbarz@madbarz.com)

## Contact

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, please send an email to: [madbarz@madbarz.com](mailto:madbarz@madbarz.com)
